{
  "easyquestions": [

    {
      "question": "Which C++ keyword is used to return a value from a function?",
      "answer1": "A) exit",
      "answer2": "B) result",
      "answer3": "C) return",
      "answer4": "D) back",
      "correct": "C) return"
    },
    {
      "question": "A statement that checks multiple conditions in sequence?",
      "answer1": "A) for",
      "answer2": "B) if",
      "answer3": "C) else",
      "answer4": "D) else if",
      "correct": "D) else if"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which C++ header file should be included to work with strings?",
      "answer1": "A) iostream",
      "answer2": "B) string",
      "answer3": "C) string.h",
      "answer4": "D) strlib.h",
      "correct": "B) string"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which C++ keyword is used to allocate memory for an array?",
      "answer1": "A) allocate",
      "answer2": "B) new",
      "answer3": "C) malloc",
      "answer4": "D) create",
      "correct": "B) new"
    },
    {
      "question": "What C++ keyword is used to define a variable that can reference an object of a class?",
      "answer1": "A) link",
      "answer2": "B) var",
      "answer3": "C) object",
      "answer4": "D) reference",
      "correct": "D) reference"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which C++ keyword is used to define an if statement?",
      "answer1": "A) if",
      "answer2": "B) test",
      "answer3": "C) check",
      "answer4": "D) verify",
      "correct": "A) if"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the correct way to include the content of \"header.h\" in a C++ program?",
      "answer1": "A) header.h",
      "answer2": "B) include <header.h>",
      "answer3": "C) include \"header.h\"",
      "answer4": "D) #include \"header.h\"",
      "correct": "D) #include \"header.h\""
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the \"else\" statement in C++?",
      "answer1": "A) To perform an action if the condition is false",
      "answer2": "B) To repeat a loop",
      "answer3": "C) To perform an action if the condition is true",
      "answer4": "D)  To end the program",
      "correct": "A) To perform an action if the condition is false"
    },
    {
      "question": " What C++ operator is used to access the value at a specific memory address?",
      "answer1": "A) %",
      "answer2": "B) +",
      "answer3": "C) *",
      "answer4": "D) /",
      "correct": "C) *"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the \"cin\" object in C++ stand for?",
      "answer1": "A) cin input",
      "answer2": "B) input",
      "answer3": "C) character input",
      "answer4": "D) console input",
      "correct": "D) console input"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which C++ function is used to print a newline?",
      "answer1": "A) /n",
      "answer2": "B) std::endl",
      "answer3": "C) endl()",
      "answer4": "D) newline;",
      "correct": "B) std::endl"
    },
    {
      "question": "What C++ keyword is used to exit from a loop prematurely?",
      "answer1": "A) stop",
      "answer2": "B) esc",
      "answer3": "C) exit",
      "answer4": "D) break",
      "correct": "D) break"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which data type is used to store true or false values in C++?",
      "answer1": "A) int",
      "answer2": "B) logical",
      "answer3": "C) bool",
      "answer4": "D) boolean",
      "correct": "C) bool"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which operator is used for logical AND in C++?",
      "answer1": "A) &&",
      "answer2": "B) &",
      "answer3": "C) &/",
      "answer4": "D) &++",
      "correct": "A) &&"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which loop in C++ runs as long as a specified condition is true?",
      "answer1": "A) for loop",
      "answer2": "B) do-while loop",
      "answer3": "C) loop",
      "answer4": "D) while loop",
      "correct": "D) while loop"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you declare a variable called \"age\" of type integer in C++?",
      "answer1": "A) age int;",
      "answer2": "B) int age;",
      "answer3": "C) integer age;",
      "answer4": "D) var age = int;",
      "correct": "B) int age;"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does C++ stand for? ",
      "answer1": "A) Computer Unification Platform",
      "answer2": "B) Computer Unified Programming+",
      "answer3": "C) C Plus Plus",
      "answer4": "D) Common Unity++",
      "correct": "C) C Plus Plus"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which C++ function is used to read input from the user? ",
      "answer1": "A) iostream",
      "answer2": "B) void",
      "answer3": "C) cout",
      "answer4": "D) cin",
      "correct": "D) cin"
    },
    {
      "question": " What is the purpose of the \"cout\" object in C++? ",
      "answer1": "A) It is used to receive input from the user.",
      "answer2": "B) It is used to perform arithmetic operations.",
      "answer3": "C) It is used to declare variables.",
      "answer4": "D) It is used to display output on the screen.",
      "correct": "D) It is used to display output on the screen."
    },
    {
      "question": " What is the purpose of the \"cin\" object in C++? ",
      "answer1": "A) It is used to perform input validation.",
      "answer2": "B) It is used to perform arithmetic operations.",
      "answer3": "C) It is used to receive input from the user.",
      "answer4": "D) It is used to display output on the screen.",
      "correct": "C) It is used to receive input from the user."
    }
  ]
}